# Cole Davis

Sugar Land, TX 77479 | 713-320-6700 | colebuildanddevelop@gmail.com Github | Portfolio | Medium | LinkedIn

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in Poker. Possess strong skills in problem solving and risk management that drives teams to confidently move towards solutions. Primarily concerned with helping and learning from others while being immersed and aligned with any given team's goals.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React, Redux, Python, Postgresgl, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, Mongoose ORM, REST API, Git, Solidity, Web3Js, Semantic-Ui, Material-UI, React-Bootstrap

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## StonkKings - Github | Website

A platform where users create and compete in stock trading competitions. Redefining traditional risk exposure.

- Backend constructed with Nodejs, Mongoose for Object relationship mapping, and MongoDb for data storage.
- Frontend built with React, Redux for central state management, and Material Ui for styling.
- Authentication handled with JSON Web Tokens.
- Fetched and visualized price data for financial products using the AlphaVantage API, and Nivo charts.
- Users enter competitions by paying an entry fee and are granted a simulated trading account to make trades with. At the end of a competition's arbitrary duration, the user with the highest account balance is granted the fees accumulated from that given competition.

### FriendsWithVids - Github | Website

A public room where users add videos to a queue for the room to watch and vote on.

- Implemented skip and up vote methods in order to create incentives to queue videos the public finds appealing.
- Developed authentication to allow users to sign in with a provided email, or with Google, using a google auth api.
- Designed a chat feature that lets users communicate in real time.
- Gave users access to edit their profile information and delete any accounts they might have created.

#### Stupid Shirts - Github | Website

A flexible e-commerce web application built with a React front end, Node backend, and Stripe API.

- Ensured PCI compliance by creating a custom Stripe checkout integration.
- Queried the stripe API using asynchronous functions and redux thunk.
- Designed to allow users to track their orders once they have checked out.
- Allows store owners to easily access customer order information through the stripe dashboard.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Kelvin Networks

**Flatiron School** 

Poker

Houston, Texas

Information Technology Support Specialist / Web Developer

01/2019 - 01/2020

- Maintained www.KelvinNetworks.com and performed SEO services increasing web presence by 50%+.
- Developed a home and small business energy monitoring and smart device control system giving clients a single page application served locally to visualize their consumption and control their devices.
- Cut product expenses by 30%+ by replacing software components with equivalent more cost effective solutions.

No Limit Hold'em Specialist

Houston, Texas 01/2017 - 01/2019

- Optimized decisions by analyzing nash equilibrium strategies derived from running a fictitious play algorithm.
- Used statistical analysis to best manage risk in the context of an assumed win rate and an accepted variance, never taking any out of scope risk.
- Maintained positive returns for 100's of thousands of hands at various stakes and game settings.
- Profitably staked and coached other players earning 50% of their profits.

### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Houston, Texas 04/2020 - 08/2020